Now we're moving on to the foundation.
We want that glowy, dewy, healthy look.
I'm using a very sheer foundation.
Almost a tinted moisturizer.
It's very hydrating and moisturizing.
It's not a matifying foundation.
If you have a drier skin type this is great.
If you have a more oiler skin type and you feel like you get very shiny, then you might want to use a more matifying foundation, but you still want to use a liquid because this is a glowy, dewy, healthy look.
You don't want it to look to flat and matte.
She has great skin, so I'm using the foundation also as a concealer around the nose, under the eyes.
You just put a little more of a concentrated amount where you need it if you want to use it as a concealer.
It all depends on what you're trying to cover.
Look up for me.
Her skin's so nice that I don't really have to use an extra concealer.
I can just use the foundation as a concealer.
If you have a blemish that really needs covering up or a scar, then you may need to go for a more heavier concealer or even a heavier foundation, depending on your skin.
Make sure you blend, blend.
You don't want it to look like you have a ton of foundation on.
You want it just to look like your skin is flawless.
Take it down the neck a little bit.
Just make sure everything is completely blended.
Then once your foundation is all blended in, take a nice pressed powder or finishing powder and dust it right on top.
Don't use too much, but use a significant amount to make sure your skin looks nice and flawless.
Don't go too much around the eye area because powder tends to seep into the lines or on the eyes.
Just stick to the face, down the neck a little bit.
Don't use too much powder.
Again, you want it to look a little more dewy, but you also want to kind of finish it off with a little bit of powder.
It just makes everything look so much smoother and nicer.
Now we're ready to do bronzer and blush.